Hello and welcome to the best react course online.
Wow that's a that's a bit of a bold statement and OK I may be biased here but I'm definitely looking
forward to us diving into some fun topics and coming out the other end as great react developers this
course tries to build onto each topic and gets more and more advanced as you progressed.
Trust me if you go through everything you will come out the other end.
Confident with react and be able to manage or even lead react projects your company now.
Before we dive into coding building projects and learning about react I want to take a moment and understand
why react exists.
What problem does it solve.
Why it makes front end development easier and also what principles we need to understand to be more
than the average react developer.
You see a lot of times people learn a tool a library or a framework without understanding the core principles
that make it great by learning these things first.
We'll have a foundation as we move through the course and understand what the best practices are.
The goal of this course is not to be another react course like thousands of others already out there
in existence.
The goal is to make you a reactive helper that can think on your own.
Make good architectural decisions and lead projects instead of only following tutorials.
Therefore in this section let's dive into the important principles that will help us get through this
course.
If you are new to react some of these principles may be hard to understand at first.
Rest assured that we will keep revisiting them throughout the course as we learn for those that have
already worked with react.
You may learn a thing or two so hang in there.
My goal by the end of this section is for you to be able to explain to other programmers the benefit
of react without writing a single line of code I do recommend that this section is something you come
back to after you've watched through the entire course.
All right enough talk let's get started.