Now react came out in 2013.
But what do we have before then before we act.
Well the front fronting landscape was very different initially back in the 90s and early 2000s.
We just had basic HMO CSX and JavaScript H2 e-mail displayed the text on our web pages see assess the
styles and JavaScript allows us to have some interactivity in a Web site.
And initially it just started with simple forms where we sent from the back end to when we go to a you
URL all these files.
And when a user let's say submits a form we simply send that back to the server to store that information.
Now if a user clicked on let's say a link in the page.
Well once again we simply request the new Asia mail file and the new page from the server and that gets
sent to the front end and that's how Web sites worked for many years.
But there is a problem here.
You see all these Web sites where run on different browsers and all these browsers were worked on by
different group of developers.
So each one of these browsers implemented while their browser differently.
So what happened was as we wanted to use more and more JavaScript in our web pages we had to account
for all these browsers that sometimes work differently from each other.
And we had to accommodate javascript to work with these different browsers.
Now eventually we had J query come out which allowed developers to easily interact with the DOM or the
document object model across all these browsers.
You see back in the day if we went to let's say hacker news over here clicked on views developer and
then developer tools and we went to elements here.
This is the DOM the dom that well is our page.
It displays exactly how our page should look like and it's a tree like structure and JavaScript.
All it does is modify this Dom.
You can remove elements you can update the elements and although there's now more similarities and compatibility
across different browsers back in the day we didn't have that.
So J query may developers happy because it had a unified easy API that kind of looked like this instead
of a developer trying to think about how to work with the DOM in each of the different browsers.
The J query said hey we'll take care of that complexity for you just this is the syntax we'll use that
works across all browsers and you can manipulate the front end or the DOM however you want so that was
great but with this power developers started building bigger and bigger applications instead of just
something small.
We started getting these massive massive applications like Facebook where you got to log in.
Look at the News Feed message friends and as websites turned into these full applications that people
can interact with besides just requesting more and more pages like a blog.
Well libraries like backbone J.S. came out because well our JavaScript files started getting bigger
and bigger and bigger libraries like backbone J.S. allowed us to organize these JavaScript files and
because it became easier and easier to work with the DOM we had the birth of a single page application.
You see traditionally we just had a small files for each page and every time we moved to a different
page we would request from the server while the asian mail file the CSF file and the javascript file
which usually contain Jacqui for each time we clicked on a link but with more advancement like we had
with J query backbone and something called Ajax we now had a different system.
What generally happened now is we focused less on HMO and a lot more in JavaScript.
You only load the application code once instead of us making new requests to the server where we returned
a new document instead.
Now our applications acted more like a desktop application where we stay on the same page the entire
time and the javascript file simply changes or updates the HMO file or the DOM to display new things.
So you were able to sign into an application and interact with that application without ever speaking
to the server anymore and this way of writing applications or single page applications became really
really popular.
And in 2010 angular J.S. which was created by Google really became the standard way of building applications
this way now unlike J angular allowed developers to build these large applications by forming these
containers that well wrapped your project and because it was created by Google it had a lot of power
because people said well this is the way that we should build things.
Everything's organized.
We have these large JavaScript files but we can organize them this way you had code now that now had
better containers where you had things like controllers views and models and this idea of a Model View
Controller where each part of the application or each JavaScript file was divided into different things
that it did this idea of organizing our large code so they're easier to work with as teams get larger
and larger really made angular J.S. popular but there was a problem.
You see things started getting more and more complex because of this.
As things get bigger and bigger more things have to happen.
Users are clicking on this button which changes this area which in turn changes this area which now
has to display this information.
We have more and more complexity now and although frameworks like angular J.S. came out people started
to notice it's getting harder and harder to find bugs in the code and understand how each part of the
app was affecting the other.
Meanwhile Facebook developers were finding it hard as well on their end to maintain their app especially
their Facebook ads.
You see the Facebook ads app got more and more features more and more people were added to the team.
Now the growing number of lines of code the growing number of people working on the app their app became
really really difficult to handle and each update would cost more and more issues where you had all
these arrows relating to each other pointing to each other.
And after a while the engineers of Facebook just couldn't keep up with the way that they had created
this app.
They needed to upgrade their code base and this isn't just special in the front end world.
This is all of our programming.
It's why we need good architecture.
We need to think about how we organize our code how we manipulate data and how that data flows through
our programs.
So Facebook came up with a solution and that solution worked really really well for them.
That in 2013 they released react to the developer community at J.S. conf 2013 and their solution was
really really good.
And it took off because react devolved a whole new way to build front end applications now.
It also happened that in 2014 angular J.S. realized that the way that they've architected their framework
just didn't allow good applications to be built anymore so they decided in 2014 that they're going to
rewrite the entire library.
Call it angular but because they wanted to do an entire rewrite a lot of people during that time moved
to react.
So combined with the fact that angular J.S. was getting a complete new rewrite Facebook was backing
react and the great principles that react introduced made it what it is today.
That is it became the most popular font and tooled with the most job demand across the world and being
used by very large companies like Airbnb be uber Netflix Twitter Reddit Pinterest Wicks PayPal stripe
Tumblr Walmart.
However what made react so great.
What were these principles that made it jump from something that Facebook used to something that developers
all over the world use.
Let's find out in the next video.