So we've learned the first two concepts.
The third concept that made to react really popular is this idea of you need directional data flow.
What do I mean by that.
Well so far we understand that React is just a javascript library that allows us to write more javascript
to have interactivity on our Web sites and in react.
We have this idea of state which you can think of it as a javascript object that describes our app.
So all the data of our app is within this state.
And then we also learned about this idea of components that we can build using react with this weird
e-mail looking thing but inside of our JavaScript files this idea of state which is the data over app
works with the components which are built using what will eventually learn is called J.S. X..
So it's a simple like syntax inside of JavaScript and These all combine to essentially give our reactive
library to things that is the components that we've built the state over application and you can think
of this as a function a react library is simply a function that we give all these things to what it's
going to do is it's going to create what we call a virtual DOM that is it creates a javascript version
of the Dom.
Remember this.
This isn't the Dom we installed the react plugin to have something that looks like the elements tab
but isn't.
Exactly.
And this is just a javascript object that describes our app into what we called this virtual Dawn which
is a tree like object like this that gives react a blueprint of how it should update the actual Dawn.
So what happens then is react.
Takes all of this and says hey here is the actual dawn or the document object model of the Web site
and the react little bot over here is going to go look at the blueprint of what it needs to build and
modifies the DOM for us now this idea of a unique directional data flow means that any time we want
something to change on our Web page.
Well the state has to change.
That is the data has to change in our app.
So what happens if as a user I click on let's say a button while I click on a button.
React is going to intercept that and say hey somebody just clicked on the bottom.
How does that.
Let's say I click on the sign up.
React is going to say hey somebody just clicked on the sign out button.
How are we going to change the state.
Well internally we would say that if somebody clicks on the sign out we're gonna change is logged in
to now say false and react as soon as the state changes reacts to that change and says hey the state
just Shane combine the new state and the components we have and update the dot you see the data only
flows one way a better way to think about this is like this our application is simply built with this
virtual Dawn.
This javascript object that describes our app and as soon as a state changes it's going to trickle down
that information and let everybody know hey the state just changed if is logged in is now false.
Display this version of the app data can never move up.
So for example the state as we'll learn can live in different locations different components and if
the state lets say changes here the data can never move up.
That is all these changes can only trickle down now.
This concept is hard to explain without actually seeing it in code.
So if you don't get this right away don't worry.
We will explore this idea and revisit this idea of one way data flow throughout the course.
But the key takeaway here is that by having this restriction of data only being able to move down from
the state of our application all the way to the DOM and if any changes or events happen that change
the state while we go back to the state and that's state change trickles down to different components
in one direction is a restriction on how data can move through our app and by adding this restriction
it's really easy to debug code.
For example if there's something wrong with our sign our function.
I can go to wherever the state is logged in lives.
Let's say it lives in this top component here I can go over here and know that this is where the bug
is happening and whatever is underneath this component.
Well that's it.
I don't have to look outside of the component of the tree was massive with thousands and millions of
components.
I only have to look in the place where the data exists and where the data flows through.
Again this is a really hard concept that we will explore throughout the course.
But this idea of one way data flow is the restriction.
And because of this restriction it's easier for us to understand how our app works unlike the arrows
and points that we saw with an angular app where things got confusing really really fast.