We learned the four main concepts that really made react takeoff.
It gave developers a whole new way to think about their applications and how we built them.
And it was architected in such a way that it made building large scale applications a lot more pleasant
than what we had before now.
Since then a lot of libraries have come out that have taken some of the react concepts angular was rewritten
to a new version that is more in line with these concepts.
Libraries like Vue are also using these concepts because people have realized that these are some really
good principles.
So now you have things like react to angular a view that developers are using to build front end applications
but react really had this initial jump and it's still the most popular library and the library with
the most job demand because it was the first to introduce these principles and the beauty is that although
we haven't written any code you've now learned a little bit about some of the key words that will encounter
throughout this course.
And don't worry you're not supposed to get them 100 percent just now because all of these things are
something that we need to practice code and build projects with to really understand them.
But now when you hear the words like declarative J.S. x component state props virtual Dawn You'll least
have an idea of what it is because we've learned that react as a declarative paradigm that is instead
of telling our apps exactly what to do.
We simply give it some state some components that are built with something called J.S. X and these components
sometimes receive properties which are called Props.
We give all that information a giant javascript object in a declarative way which creates a virtual
DOM in JavaScript in that virtual DOM is used by the react library to update the DOM for us in a declarative
way but your question is this how do I become the best reactive helper I can be and to be a great reactive
helper.
It actually comes down to three things three things that really really good senior reactive operas do
well and we're going to focus on these three skills throughout the course.
The first one is to decide on components really good reactive helpers decide what is a component.
How much do we want to break down a component.
How do we build these reusable components.
As we've seen in deciding on how to break down the app into different components is a very important
skill.
The next thing is to decide the state and where it lives.
Now we're going to explore this idea of state or data of our app a lot more.
But this state can live in different locations in our virtual dorm so whether we put the state here
or we put the state here or here or here or in multiple locations.
That decision is very important in architecting your app and really good react developers do a really
good job placing state in the appropriate component.
The third is what changes should we make when the state changes based on what this javascript object
called state is changed.
We have to decide what to render what part of the virtual DOM changes and deciding on this is also important
because it has huge effects on performance.
Now don't worry these are the things that we're going to really work on but I want you to keep this
as a reference because if you want to become a senior react developer These are the things that you
have to become really good at making these decisions and knowing when something is good when when something
is bad.
We're going to explore that and a lot more in the next section.
I'll see in the next one.
Bobby.