We know that we can write functions that return HMO but we can also write classes that return HMO.
And the reason why we would want to use a class is because react has given us the ability to write classes
that have a lot more functionality on them versus a function that returns some HMO.
Now let me show you this.
So in order to write a class we've got a first import component from react and instead of this function
and I'm going to convert this into a class so class app extends this component that we get from reactive.
And as a result we now have access to this render method inside of our app class and the render method
returns any HDMI want.
So let's return that HMO we had before inside of our function and we'll see that it's actually the same
and to prove it.
I'm gonna change this tag.
This text here and we should see an update right.
Hello Iowa.
So this is great so it's pretty much the exact same at this point as are functional app that we had
before right.
Our function app that returned this block of H.
But the reason why we would want to use this kind of thing is if we wanted say instead to display this
static string of Hello You are what if I wanted something like let's say instead of an A tag we had
a button and whenever you click this button it would change the text to something else.
Right.
We would change this hello you want to something else well the thing about that is that by using a class
component we actually get access to this thing called state what state is is it some object right.
A javascript object with properties that we can access at any point inside of our class.
And the way we would do this is we would actually call the constructor keyword here and inside of a
constructor we want to call super right.
And what super does is it calls the constructor method on the component class.
And what that does is it gives us access to this dot state right.
This state property now exists on our class app and we can set it to something.
So this is the default value.
I want to set it to first.
So let's say I want to set it to the string that we have right now.
Right.
I want to set some property on our state object too.
Hello Iowa and then I want to render that instead of.
Hello Iowa.
The static string right.
How would I do that.
Well I would first use these curly braces which Jeff Sachs lets us do and it tells the HD and all that.
Anything between these curly braces is going to be JavaScript So I want you to render javascript right.
So we want to do this dot state DOT string and now between these p tags we watch you won't see anything
change because it's the same string but just to.
I want to say hello.
E was saying right there we see that it's looking at the state looking at this property string and rendering
that here instead so that's awesome because now I can do this in multiple places right.
I can use this as many times as I want and I'm going to see multiple versions of it right so what if
I wanted to change this value while the way I would do it is this class app that extends component this
component also gives us this method called set state and what sets state does is it lets us modify this
state object right on every single H html element.
We now have access to this method this property called on click which takes a function that gets called
when ever this element gets clicked so let's pass in this function and in this function we're gonna
say this dot set state and what's that say takes is an object with all of the properties that you want
to change on your state as well as the new values that they have.
So I want to change the property string to Hello Andre.
Now when I click this button it will see that it changed right.
And that's really awesome because this gives us a lot of control over what we want our components to
display.
So this will be really really useful later when we don't know where we're going to get some of the information
that we actually want to display inside of our HCM out but I'm going to show you in the next lesson
why this is really useful.