Hey there it's Andre here.
Wanted to add a quick note a few things that you may have been confused about.
You may be asking why we changed this from a function to a class and older versions of create react
app actually started the app with a class instead of a function.
Now this topic of classes versus functions is something that we're going to cover more and more in-depth
as we get through the course and especially towards the end when we talk about react hooks now to go
through with this code.
We need to understand a few things.
The very first thing is that this syntax of jazz sex which we're going to talk a little bit more about.
But for now it looks like everything is just an 80 mile tack.
However because this is javascript there's a few changes.
One is that this class name over here that's not a shemale is it.
And if I hover over this you see that it's a j a sex attribute.
You see because if I used the word class in here class means something else in JavaScript it means well
we're creating a class right.
So Jeff Sachs uses the syntax of class name to distinguish between what we actually mean which is the
actually giving it an ACM all class vs. a class in JavaScript.
The other thing.
Are these brackets over here.
You see how every time we write these curly brackets inside of our JSA X well they mean inside of here.
Anytime you see these curly brackets whatever's inside is a javascript expression.
So what does that mean.
Well logo is a variable which is the logo that we import.
This dot state DOT string.
Well that's also a variable which is referring to this state.
It's a javascript expression it's something that produces a value.
For example I could have done four plus five here if I wanted to because it's a javascript expression
another place that we see this is right here with the on click again anything around these brackets
is a javascript expression.
So what's in here.
There's a function right.
An anonymous function using this arrow syntax that simply calls this dot set state now.
Notice here how we don't actually modify this dot set state like this.
This dot state DOT string to equal something else like we would normally and this goes back to the idea
that I mentioned previously which is this unique directional data flow of react.
You see you're not allowed to modify state in react without calling this method set state.
Now why is that because any time we change the state let's say a user clicks that button to change the
state to a new string.
When that click happens what happens is react actually.
Intercept because remember react as the one that's talking to the DOM.
It's going to intercept that click and it's going to report back and say Hey I got to click on the Dom.
What do I do.
Well in this case what we're going to say is on click when the click happens I want you to update the
state but we're not going to modify the state automatically.
I'm going to say hey a click happened.
State gets updated using set state and then that change is going to re render the components so that
we can go through this flow again again if we look over here as soon as this set state gets called which
is when a click happens.
Well what's going to happen this render method gets called again.
Why does it get called.
Well because state just got updated state now is a different thing.
And remember the declarative approach with react is that as soon as state changes we re render the component
with the new state which is right here and we display that.
Now this on click is that HMO.
Well if I hover over here it says no that's a J sex attribute.
Again remember this isn't HMO.
This is javascript.
We're just mimicking HMO.
So if I wanted to say use on click an HMO you see that on click is run like this with no capital C because
in JavaScript we use camel case.
It's a capital C..
So just like Kos name was a little bit different than HMO on click is also different.
So in react we can use whatever HMO attributes that we want.
Like source like class like on click but sometimes there's these differences like class name or on click.
Now we're going to explore these different attributes throughout the course.
But the key thing to remember is that Jeff Sachs is trying to mimic what HMO does.
So with that we can create that virtual Dawn and breakdown each part of the app into these components
that keep getting re rendered as we update the state using said state let's keep going.