Now let's start making our application resemble more closely to our actual final monster's Rolodex application
so we know that we need to display a list of monsters.
So instead of this string Halloween.
I'm gonna make a new property called Monsters and I'm going to make it an array of objects that have
a name on it.
That's a string value.
So our first monster will be Frankenstein our second monster will be Dracula and our third monster will
be a zombie.
So here I want to render let's say just a bunch of H ones with the actual names of these monsters.
Right.
So how I would go about doing that is I'm going to get rid of this because we don't need this anymore
and we write our curly braces because we've got to render some javascript right.
So now between these curly braces we can really render any javascript that we want.
So I am going to call this dot state DOT monsters dot map because map returns us the return of whatever
function we pass to it iterated over every element in this array.
Right.
So when I say iterate what I mean is that this function that I write here whatever this returns it's
going to return in the place of every element in this array.
So I'm gonna call a map on this monster's array right and map takes a function where the first argument
is going to be the actual element that this function is going to get called on.
Right.
So it's going to call the function we pass in on it on Frankenstein and then on Dracula and then on
the zombie.
Right.
It's going to call it on each object.
Now what that function returns will be what gets return out of this map.
Usually it's a new array.
Right.
When you call a map but react is smart enough to know that if we end up rendering out a bunch of h t
AML blocks right in an array then it will just display those elements.
So let's take a look.
So our first element right our first argument is monster.
So I'm going to return a new H1
H1 where I'm going to again call the curly braces because this is a new return block right of HDL.
Just like here.
Right.
It's gonna need new curly braces.
And inside I'm gonna call monster.
Name now what we should see is the name of each of our monsters right.
We see that now.
If we open up our console we'll see this warning that says each child in a list should have a unique
key prop.
So it's asking us to add a unique key to every child that gets a turn out of this map.
Right.
We've got to provide something that is unique completely to this list of elements.
So let's just make a value of I.D. and just call it something like this.
Right.
And any random unique string will work.
The reason why we want a unique key is because react needs to know what element it needs to update.
If one of these elements in our array has a value that changes right now let's say for example the user
does something and it changes the name of our first monster from Frankenstein to Banshee for example.
Right.
Like let's say it does it in the code somewhere like the same way that we saw when we called set state
earlier.
Well react is smart enough to know that it only needs to update that first H1 right to change it to
that new the new property.
It doesn't need to re render all of these.
And the key helps react understand it helps it know which element is the one that's been updated.
Right which HDMI is attached to.
Which element.
So that it knows that it doesn't have to render everything.
You can see how if this list was way bigger it would be really performance heavy to re render all everything.
And that's what makes react so great.
It's that it's smart it knows that if only one element in a list of a thousand elements changes it only
needs to re render the part of the HDMI all that matters not the whole thing.
So now that we have our list we actually want to make this look closer to the final.
So right now these are just place holders for us to understand a little bit more of what it's like to
write react.
Right.
We're iterating over an array and creating new elements.
But let's actually dive a little deeper into it.