Welcome back.
In the next video we're going to start talking about something called lifecycle methods and API is no
one in order to prepare for that lesson.
I want to go over something that we already saw.
There is this component class app extends component.
Now what does that really mean component.
If we look here is part of the react library and we're using de structuring here.
But if I didn't include it like this I could still use it using the react dot component because component
well is a property on react that we can use.
And when we do something like class app extends react component.
What we're doing is saying hey I want whatever functionality that this a react component that was already
built into the library by somebody.
I want that functionality and I'm going to add onto it.
So for example this render method comes built in with real component in this react component gives us
some batteries included options to use in our component so that we don't have to constantly repeat ourself
we use something that reacts says hey this is a component and we just tack on some specific functionality
to it as you'll see we'll learn about lifecycle methods and how these components have some important
methods already on them such as if I type in CRM here you'll see that I have some methods that comes
from the react dot component lifecycle but we'll get to that shortly.
Another thing I want to talk about is this idea of an API remember how we talked about the birth of
the single page application.
How initially all we had to do with a normal web page was we visited a link and we got the Asian all
javascript and assets file when we clicked on another link.
We went to a different page.
So we got a whole new 80 mile javascript and assets file however with single page applications.
We now have this idea of communicating with the backend initially where we get a tiny Asia male page.
Remember with our just ideas of route where we fill in our ReACT component and then we have this massive
JavaScript file or a least bigger than he usually was with our ReACT library with our components with
any of our logic.
So now instead of having to communicate back and forth with the server if I click on something and let's
say visit a different part of the page I don't have to go back I can just have a javascript or react
say hey just we rendered the DOM with something else.
So now with a single page application instead of requesting a page it's turn more into requesting for
data.
And this is when we have the ability to let's say communicate with outside servers maybe servers that
we don't control.
For example in our big project we're going to talk to the Google firebase database we might talk to
some different API endpoints so that now we can communicate with different API is back and forth and
using JavaScript just receive the data for example we saw that this Jason Place holder Web site by entering
into this Web site all I get is well not an Asia MLP trade.
All I get is this data that is formatted in what we call Jason.
So this Jason data can be converted into let's say a javascript object that we can use.
But all this does is provide us an API a way for us to access information from well this server so that
now single page applications instead of just rendering AML can use this data to perhaps display different
monsters different to user information.
And as we'll see it will allow us to do interesting things like sign in sign out add items to the shopping
cart and we'll explore that idea throughout the course and by the way.
There's a way for you to actually check this if we open up our developer tools and we go to network
and I refresh the page here.
You'll see that I have this user's this users document if I click on it and if I go to response we see
that this is the response that we get.
So as you start to build larger and larger applications what you'll find is that you'll start talking
to API eyes and trying to get different data for your application and these end points or servers that
we speak to can be third party servers like Google servers or they can be your own server where you
perhaps have your own database.
Now that's something that we explore a little bit more later on.
But the key thing is that the way we build applications now is very dynamic most of the time we don't
hard code all the information into these files.
Instead when a user opens something we are always communicating with outside servers.
So we're going to start structuring our app this way let's keep on.