So we just learned how to take an array on our state and turn it into elements that we can then see
right now in a real world scenario.
We're probably not going to hard code the information that we're going to have right.
Normally we would probably get it from a back end of some kind some kind of server some kind of database
so I'm gonna show you how that would actually work.
Now luckily I have a pretty good resource where it will give us a sample of 10 users right without us
having to actually build a back end server of some kind.
And it's at this link.
Well it will give us back is this array of these objects right that have these properties like I.D.
and name and email on it that we will use for our application.
So what we need to figure out is how do we get this app component to make a call to the back end and
then put that data into our states so that our render function knows to use it.
Right nodes can have access to it.
So how do we do that.
You see.
You remember how we got the render method by extending into component.
We also get a bunch of other methods that are called lifecycle.
What are lifecycle methods.
Well if we look at this here we see a list of all these methods and it's an overwhelming list but what
lifecycle methods are is there.
Essentially methods that get called at different stages of when this component gets rendered.
Now I know that's kind of jargon right now but I'm going to explain it to you throughout this course.
But the main one I want us to focus on is component did mount.
Now what component did mount does is it's kind of like the name right when this component mounts mounting
is essentially one react puts our component on the page right.
It renders it onto the DOM for the first time when it does that it red it calls whatever block of code
we write inside of here.
That's all it does.
So what we want to do is we want to use javascript native fetch right to fetch from that you or I'll
make an API request to that you are all and what this fetch returns us is a promise.
Right.
But that promise gives us a response of the actual body of our response but we don't know what that
looks like at first.
Right.
So let's just log it out and see so we see this response object right.
It's got the body and it's got these headers it's got all these properties that we don't really care
about we don't really need them.
Right.
The main thing we want is we want the body but we want it in a format that our javascript understands
in the format of Jason right.
So let's from here return response Don.
Jason which is a method.
Right.
On this response object that will give us back that response in the Jason format which we want and then
that will get returned to us as a new promise which we will now have as the body which will be this
array so when we get that array let's just log in again so that we know what we're getting
we see our array right in the format in the objects that we know and we can use.
So what we want to do is now we want to call set state as we did before.
But now we want to set our monsters to this array of these users right and we want our initial state
to be an empty array because we don't need to hardcoded anymore.
Right.
We're just going to we're going to wait for our component to mount and then we're going to fetch all
of our users and then we're going to update our state's monster property with this new array of users.
And now when we check our application we see that we have all of our monsters or users.
Right.
And we're displaying alternate.
Now we see this error here.
Right.
It's just a warning.
And it's telling us that we're not using the logo anymore.
So let's just get rid of it.
That's the great thing about create racked up as well is it comes with lynching.
We can be aware of writing and making our code clean.
So now just to go over this again we're using this component did mount lifecycle method that we have
access to because of our class component and we are fetching from this you are all we are taking a response
and converting it into the Jason format that are JavaScript can understand and use and then we're going
to take the users that we got back from it and set our monsters to that array of user and that's how
we end up with this list of in the next section we're going to now convert this to look a little bit
closer to this.