Now before we get into the next video where we're going to build some of these components and actually
start making our app I want to go over something you notice here that we're rendering this app which
isn't HMO but our own custom component that is we're importing this app file which is app.
And don't worry about this code.
This is something that we're going to write later on but we see over here that we're returning under
the render some HMO.
Now the way you react works is that we can combine these HMO like elements such as Dev or H1 but also
create our own custom ones like we will like search box or card list.
And just like we saw on our developer tools with react these components we have capital letters and
I've use some highlighting here so that it doesn't highlight them you can see the difference between
a component that we built which starts with a capital letter and a component that comes pre-built and
reacts which are like a schmo Dave or H1.
These are lowercase and as you remember with the react component architecture all we're doing is just
creating and combining these Lego blocks together and the syntax is either using the class syntax with
a capital letter.
So now we can use the app component or if we go to something like search box or car list let's do a
search box again we won't have this here but we will build them over the next couple of videos you'll
see that here I have a different way of building a component and this use this just an arrow function.
So remember when we first did the create react app how we had function search box or in our case we
had the app backed in here we returned some J OSX like H1 well this is the same thing except that we're
using the arrow function way.
So there's two ways like this of creating components the class component and functional component.
Now that's something that we're gonna go get into a lot because it's an important concept and react
and has some implications but we're getting ahead of ourselves.
The key here is to realize that we have for now two ways of building components either just as functions
like this again using capital naming system or using classes like this and both of these no matter what
always returns some sort of J asks for us some sort of react elements now another thing I want to mention
is the folder structure that we're going to build throughout our course and a good folder structure
is really really important on any project as projects get bigger and bigger as we get more and more
JavaScript files.
Things are going to get complicated so we need to be organized.
So we're gonna be structuring our app like a lot of professional reactive helpers ha so that we stay
organized and what you'll notice here is that e war when creating components likes being very explicit.
That is if a component in this component folder has J.S. X in it he actually ends the file with DOT
J as sex and you see we have that little react icon.
If I go down to the bottom over here you see that it's javascript react so J.S. X simply means it's
javascript but with this J.S. X syntax.
Now if I change this to a simple JavaScript file it's still going to work.
It's why app does J.S. still works the way it does and this is actually just personal preference.
This is how e while enjoys organizing his code because this right away I can look at it and say oh this
is a react JavaScript or J x file.
But at the end of the day remember create react app takes everything through Westpac and Babel will
actually convert this J sex file into a javascript file.
So whether you do J sex or jazz it doesn't really matter.
Maybe your editor will help you with an icon but that's about it.
It's just personal preference.
It's all about structuring your application in a way that's easy to understand that makes sense.
Even the naming convention here is important.
Where again just by looking at the file even though it's in the components folder right away I know.
Oh yeah.
This is a component and this is the style for the component now.
These styles these C assessed files that we're gonna be writing and trust me we're gonna be writing
a lot of them at the end of the day what happens underneath the hood is that create react app combines
everything altogether.
And if you remember if we go back to our test folder when we run NPM run built and we go to the C file
you see over here that we have a chunk of CSX with a dot map.
This is a source map which just helps us debug our code and production but we have just one massive
CSX file and that's what create react app does even though we'll have different C Ss files in our workspace
in our source folder at the end of the day when we release to production all of these are going to get
combined together and although we're still early in the course although we haven't really built all
these components I want to start noticing these things as we build things.
We're going to be thinking about how to stay organized instead of just having all the files in one directory
instead of not having any organization right from the beginning of the project.
We're starting to think about how we want to architect it and this is an important principle that we're
going to take with us through all the rest of the course let's keep on.